But then in the writer I talk about something
called after stage I just wanted to mention
that very quickly, so what is an after state
now it is a very interesting concept yeah
what is in after State, yeah so in many problem
instances especially things like games or
like this kind of a civil mean like a system
where that is moves by nature right so there
are moves by the human the moves by nature
or moves by an opponent right.
So that is the whole stochastic city in the
system is introduced either by this opponent
or by nature right you are actions the effects
of your actions on the system are deterministic
right but you do not know what the opponent
will do right so in this case of nature is
like cows aging and things like that so your
action is selling cows that is deterministic
if you send a cow the cow is gone from you
right you know that effect right.
You make a move then the piece moves right
there is no stochastic there right when I
want to move upon on the board I put it there
well as long as you do not have Parkinson's
or something okay it will actually land up
in the square that you wanted to go right
and well you have to consider all eventualities
right but then you do not know what the opponent
is going to do right so if you look at the
actual state transition dynamics it is going
to look stochastic.
But that is a deterministic component and
then there is a stochastic component so sometimes
it makes it a lot more convenient to come
up with a solution if you pull out the deterministic
component separately and represent s x a as
an after state right so what is an after state
it is some sense you take your S right you
apply A to it so you get to some other space
which we will call s’ and now all your stochastic
is applied to state in s’ right and this
will result in a in a state S right so this
is essentially what is happening so S x A
yet S’, S’ to s so if I am going to represent
things as s after states instead of learning
a Q function I can learn a value over the
elements in after States.
I can learn a V function over the entries
in s prime this is essentially a combination
of s x a so the v function over s’ is almost
like learning a Q function and what is the
advantage of learning this v function over
s’ instead of q / s x a, I have one less
dimension and anything else one less dimension
okay then I explained that in the writer so
it could be that many state action paths yield
the same s’ right.
I actually talked about this very briefly
talking about Tic Tac toe I told you there
are many different ways in which you could
have come here right so I do not care which
way you got the right I could have for example
I could have from there I could go that right
offer
I could go there right so this is a state
and the action was put across there and this
is the state the action was put across here
but both have the same after state.
And since the evaluation from here is going
to be the same but this is an after state
right this is a state this is after state
right so you see why I denoted the after state
by S’ why, a tic-tac-toe S is going to have
an equal number of X and O’s, s’ will
have one next more than O and if I am playing
x whenever I see the board whenever I have
to make a move that will be equal number of
X and O’s right.
But not the state will have one next more
than O right so it is actually different set
of states they are not really States I mean
I might or might not see them in reality for
example in the cow task after states are possibly
states I mean cannot be stated it they are
also states like they are also stays after
sets are also states but in detect O case
after states are not steps because you will
never see a state that has a more access than
O’s.
So that is why that is why I denote it this
is s’ as a separate thing it could be the
same as S but it could also be different but
the point here was this is actually a QSA
right I mean if I learn a value function over
the states its QSA and since the whole thing
is deterministic.
.
If I know the rules of the game I can do the
look-ahead so I give you a state I look at
all possible after States and then I pick
an action which leads me to the best possible
after state, now I can do the look ahead because
it is only the application of the action I
do not have to model nature and I only have
to model what happens when I apply my action
to it so it is a possible look ahead and this
is how Gerry Tesauro implemented is backgammon
also.
Now he did not learn a value function over
state axles you learn to value function over
after States right back and also write once
the die roll is determined that you take an
action right when you take an action your
state includes the die roll and once you know
the die roll then whatever action you do the
effects will be deterministic and then they
are opponent will actually make a non-deterministic
move so that is fine, okay any questions?
Okay so that means is the end of chapter 6
so at some point I will do some proof sketches
for TD 0 and possibly q-learning but it might
not be next week we will see and so next I
will start off on Chapter seven.